Fred Crawford Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Fred Crawford Papers
1892 – 2008
NPkMC-222-218
98 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Marist College
The Fred Crawford Papers consists of the research material gathered by Central Michigan University Professor Fred Crawford from 1991 to 1998 for a biography on Lowell Thomas.
Collection Overview
The Fred Crawford Papers consists of the research material gathered by Central Michigan University Professor Fred Crawford from 1991 to 1998 for a biography on Lowell Thomas. Most of the material within the collection appears to have been maintained in an orderly fashion by Fred Crawford. The lone exception to this is Series 2 which may have been the material Crawford was currently working on as well as assorted on-hand and reference material. While the order within most of the file series was not maintained during the transport to Marist College, the original order was recreated during processing based on the detail of Crawford’s original folder descriptions. These descriptions were maintained when possible with alterations made only for consistency and completion. Misfiles that appeared to be organic were maintained to preserve as much of Crawford’s original and unique order as possible.
Acquisitions Information
The Fred Crawford Papers were gathered from 1991 to 1998 by Fred Crawford while he was researching the life of Lowell Thomas for a planned biography. After his death, his wife MaryAnn Crawford (also a CMU professor of English) attempted to sell the collection to another researcher that would take up the challenge of a Thomas biography. She may or may not have contributed to the comprehensive labeling and organization of the collection. After she was unable to find a buyer, she donated the collection to Marist College in 2012.
Historical Note
Fred Crawford was Professor of English at Central Michigan University who researched Lowell Thomas for a biography from 1991 – 1998.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Collection is arranged into thirteen series: 1) Original Material from Lowell Thomas Papers, has three subseries, 2) Fred Crawford mixed research and reference file, 3) IOC File: Individual research correspondence, 4) AC: Administrative Correspondence, 5) External research file, 6) Lowell Thomas papers research file, 7) AMT File, 8) Marianna Munn Thomas file, 9) Boxed chronological materials=, has four subseries, 10) Photographs, 11) Objects, 12)Audio Recordsings, has eight subseries, and 13, Video Tapes
Materials are arranged by subject or chronologically
- 1. Original material from Lowell Thomas Papers, 1; Boxes: 1 - 10
  Series contains materials from series 2, series 6, and series 9
  Subject
  - Subseries 1.1 Original` material from Series 2, 1.1; Box: 1
    - Bibliography Checks (moved from Series 2: Administrative file), undated (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Subseries 1.2 Original material from Series 6, 1.2; Boxes: 1 - 10
    - Admirals Dinner, 1950 April 11 (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - Address, 1930 - 1956 (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - Order of Adventures, 1930 - 1964 (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - Advertising Club, 1937 - 1974 (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - Afghanistan Relief Committee, 1980 (Folder 6, Box 1)
    - Age, 1944 - 1978 (Folder 7, Box 1)
    - Akin hall Association, 1940 - 1971 (Folder 8, Box 1)
    - Alaska, 1914 - 1917 (Folder 9, Box 1)
    - Alaska, 1933 - 1981 (Folder 10, Box 1)
    - Alaska Fire, 1974 June 20 (Folder 11, Box 1)
    - Alaska Methodist W, 1969 - 1971 (Folder 12, Box 1)
    - Alaska - Nepal, 1968 (Folder 13, Box 1)
    - Alaska Parks, 1967 - 1970 (Folder 14, Box 1)
    - Alaska Quake, 1964 (Folder 15, Box 1)
    - Albi 331, 1941 - 1921 (Folder 16, Box 1)
    - Algermissen, Henry, 1945 - 1949 (Folder 17, Box 1)
    - American Colony, 1931 - 1958 (Folder 18, Box 1)
    - American Colony, 1959 - 1970 (Folder 19, Box 1)
    - American Colony Aid Assoco Gen, 1930 - 1961 (Folder 20, Box 1)
    - American Colony Peale, 1955 - 1965 (Folder 21, Box 1)
    - Am [American] Field Service, undated (Folder 22, Box 1)
    - American Platform Guild, 1917 - 1957 (Folder 23, Box 1)
    - Am [American] School for Boys, Baghdad, 1939 - 1953 (Folder 24, Box 1)
    - American School - JAY, 1940 (Folder 25, Box 1)
    - Am [American] U [University] of Beirut, 1949 - 1976 (Folder 26, Box 1)
    - Anthony, Gene, 1962 - 1981 (Folder 27, Box 1)
    - Appearances, 1928 - 1981 (Folder 28, Box 1)
    - Arizona Flowers, 1969 - 1971 (Folder 29, Box 1)
    - Arna, 1942 - 1974 (Folder 30, Box 1)
    - Arnold, HAP, 1946 - 1973 (Folder 31, Box 1)
    - Atomic, 1945 - 1950 (Folder 32, Box 1)
    - Atomic Tests (French), 1963 - 1964 (Folder 33, Box 1)
    - Audience, 1932 - 1975 (Folder 34, Box 1)
    - Aussie Cutting Book, 1920 (Folder 35, Box 1)
    - Auto Bio [Autobiography], 1947 - 1975 (Folder 36, Box 1)
    - Automobiles, 1941 - 1979 (Folder 37, Box 1)
    - Aviation, 1917 - 1981 (Folder 38, Box 1)
    - Aviation Hall of Fame, 1968 - 1981 (Folder 39, Box 1)
    - Awards, 1927 - 1981 (Folder 40, Box 1)
    - Back to M, 1944 - 1962 (Folder 41, Box 1)
    - Baker, Man of the Press, 1963 - 1981 (Folder 42, Box 1)
    - Banquet, 1965 November 22 (Folder 43, Box 1)
    - Bell Portrait (Bodley), 1935 - 1981 (Folder 44, Box 1)
    - Berge, Victor, 1931 - 1956 (Folder 45, Box 1)
    - Berry Lane, 1970 (Folder 1, Box 2)
    - Best Years, 1978 - 1982 (Folder 2, Box 2)
    - Bikini Tests, 1946 (Folder 3, Box 2)
    - Billo, Pat Ryan, 1959 - 1980 (Folder 4, Box 2)
    - Biographer (Dean), 1981 (Folder 5, Box 2)
    - Biographer (Ferguson), 1939 - 1943 (Folder 6, Box 2)
    - Birnbryer, 1956 - 1980 (Folder 7, Box 2)
    - Birthdays, 1941 - 1981 (Folder 8, Box 2)
    - Blades for Britain, 1941 - 1942 (Folder 9, Box 2)
    - Blair, Frank, 1976 - 1980 (Folder 10, Box 2)
    - Blonde Captive, 1932 - 1976 (Folder 11, Box 2)
    - Bohemian Grove, 1939 - 1981 (Folder 12, Box 2)
    - Boh [Bohemian] Grove, 1968 - 1981 (Folder 13, Box 2)
    - Book Ideas, 1931 - 1979 (Folder 14, Box 2)
    - Book of the High MTs [Mountains], 1945 - 1968 (Folder 15, Box 2)
    - Braley, 1938 - 1969 (Folder 16, Box 2)
    - Broadcast Excerpts, 1939 - 1975 (Folder 17, Box 2)
    - Broadcast Guests, 1933 - 1964 (Folder 18, Box 2)
    - Broadcast (remote & customs), 1957 - 1969 (Folder 19, Box 2)
    - Broadcast, 1930 - 1951 (Folder 20, Box 2)
    - Buranell, Prosper, 1931 - 1960 (Folder 21, Box 2)
    - Burke, Tom, 1940 - 1953 (Folder 22, Box 2)
    - Burma Jack, 1959 - 1980 (Folder 23, Box 2)
    - Burton, Dorothy, 1958 - 1972 (Folder 24, Box 2)
    - Burwell (Uranium), 1948 - 1949 (Folder 25, Box 2)
    - Bush [George], 1977 - 1981 (Folder 26, Box 2)
    - Callahan, Alston, 1967 - 1981 (Folder 27, Box 2)
    - Campbell, Robert, 1938 - 1981 (Folder 28, Box 2)
    - Campbell Flap, 1969 (Folder 29, Box 2)
    - Cap [Capital] Cities [Communication, Inc.], 1946 - 1981 (Folder 30, Box 2)
    - Carnegie, Dale, 1934 - 1978 (Folder 31, Box 2)
    - Cars: Accidents and Insurance, 1932 - 1954 (Folder 32, Box 2)
    - CBS, 1932 - 1981 (Folder 33, Box 2)
    - CBS and LTJ [Lowell Thomas, Jr.], 1954 - 1960 (Folder 34, Box 2)
    - CBS Lines, 1946 - 1969 (Folder 35, Box 2)
    - Charmonz, 1938 - 1981 (Folder 36, Box 2)
    - 18 Chu Gents AMX, 1917 - 1981 (Folder 37, Box 2)
    - Chi - Kent School of Law, 1914 - 1981 (Folder 38, Box 2)
    - Christ Church (QH [Quaker Hill], 1935 - 1981 (Folder 39, Box 2)
    - Christl, 1947 - 1976 (Folder 40, Box 2)
    - Christl Book, 1963 - 1966 (Folder 41, Box 2)
    - Christmas Card (Signed), undated (Folder 42, Box 2)
    - Christmas Lists, 1940 - 1949 (Folder 43, Box 2)
    - Cinerama, 1950 - 1953 March (Folder 44, Box 2)
    - Cinerama, 1953 April - 1955 (Folder 1, Box 3)
    - Cinerama, 1956 - 1980 (Folder 2, Box 3)
    - Cin - and Hi Ad, 1958 (Folder 3, Box 3)
    - Damascus Fair, 1954 (Folder 4, Box 3)
    - Datable?, 1957 March 8 (Folder 5, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] Essay Contest, 1953 (Folder 6, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] Gov [ Government], 1953 - 1959 (Folder 7, Box 3)
    - CINIKE (Cinerama), 1952 - 1956 (Folder 8, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] Ideas, 1953 - 1959 (Folder 9, Box 3)
    - Cin - India, 1956 - 1958 (Folder 10, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] Legal, ETC, 1951 - 1956 (Folder 11, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] - Reisini, 1959 - 1963 (Folder 12, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] - Programs, 1952 - 1958 (Folder 13, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] - Remote, 1954 - 1956 (Folder 14, Box 3)
    - Search - Accident, 1956 - 1960 (Folder 15, Box 3)
    - Search - GOV'T [Government], 1956 - 1958 (Folder 16, Box 3)
    - Search - Gov't [Government] (Vaccine), 1956 (Folder 17, Box 3)
    - Search - Lang, 1956 - 1957 (Folder 18, Box 3)
    - Search - Legal, 1956 - 1957 (Folder 19, Box 3)
    - Search - Personnel, 1956 - 1957 (Folder 20, Box 3)
    - Search Reitzel, Bok, 1956 (Folder 21, Box 3)
    - Search - Remote CBS, 1956 (Folder 22, Box 3)
    - Search Reviews, 1956 - 1957 (Folder 23, Box 3)
    - Final Script Continuity "Search For Paradise", undated (Folder 24, Box 3)
    - Search - Seawall, Barbara Jean, 1956 - 1966 (Folder 25, Box 3)
    - 7W Apprec, 1955 - 1957 (Folder 26, Box 3)
    - 7W [7 Wonders] Book, 1955 - 1974 (Folder 27, Box 3)
    - 7W [7 Wonders] Mantz, 1954 - 1955 (Folder 28, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] 7W [7 Wonders] Mats, 1955 (Folder 29, Box 3)
    - 7W [7 Wonders] Pan Am, 1954 - 1955 (Folder 30, Box 3)
    - Cin [Cinerama] 7W Chruchill and Murrow, 1954 - 1955 (Folder 1, Box 4)
    - Cin [Cinerama] 7W [7 Wonders] Open, 1956 - 1957 (Folder 2, Box 4)
    - 7W [7 Wonders] Gov't [Government], 1952 - 1958 (Folder 3, Box 4)
    - 7W Pub and Reviews, 1956 - 1960 (Folder 4, Box 4)
    - 7W [7 Wonders] Odds and Ends, 1954? (Folder 5, Box 4)
    - Cinerama Technology, 1950 - 1957 (Folder 6, Box 4)
    - This [is Cinerama] Credits, undated (Folder 7, Box 4)
    - Cin [Cinerama] - This, 1951 - 1956 (Folder 8, Box 4)
    - This [This is Cinerama] Openings, 1953 (Folder 9, Box 4)
    - This [This is Cinerama] Tickets, Apprec (?), Extracts (?), 1952 - 1957 (Folder 10, Box 4)
    - Circumnavigators, 1934 - 1981 (Folder 11, Box 4)
    - Clark, Mark, 1945 - 1979 (Folder 12, Box 4)
    - Colex Weber Commercial, 1980 (Folder 13, Box 4)
    - Colo [Colorado] Ranch (Tiffany), 1931 - 1946 (Folder 14, Box 4)
    - Comfort, Mildred, 1962 - 1980 (Folder 15, Box 4)
    - Compton (Advertising), 1946 - 1955 (Folder 16, Box 4)
    - Conventions, 1936 (Folder 17, Box 4)
    - Conventions, 1948 (Folder 18, Box 4)
    - Convention, 1952 (Folder 19, Box 4)
    - Cooper, Pherbia, 1938 - 1981 (Folder 20, Box 4)
    - Cousins, Bob, 1955 - 1959 (Folder 21, Box 4)
    - Cowling, Herford tunes, 1929 - 1946 (Folder 22, Box 4)
    - Creel, George, 1931 - 1947 (Folder 23, Box 4)
    - Cripple Creek, 1918 - 1981 (Folder 24, Box 4)
    - Critics, 1931 - 1979 (Folder 25, Box 4)
    - Crosley Radio, 1935 - 1942 (Folder 26, Box 4)
    - Davis - Endorse, 1940 (Folder 27, Box 4)
    - Davis, Mary, to John Lerch on Hi Ad [High Adventure], 1964 (Folder 28, Box 4)
    - Debts (old), 1928 - 1942 (Folder 29, Box 4)
    - Denver University, 1932 - 1981 (Folder 30, Box 4)
    - Denver U [University] Days, 1913 - 1962 (Folder 31, Box 4)
    - Dewey, 1937 - 1980 (Folder 32, Box 4)
    - Dinner - Storrst, 1939 January 11 (Folder 33, Box 4)
    - Dionne Quints, 1935 - 1946 (Folder 34, Box 4)
    - Dogs, 1934 - 1979 (Folder 35, Box 4)
    - Doolittle, Jimmy, 1929 - 1981 (Folder 36, Box 4)
    - Doubleday, 1930 - 1980 (Folder 37, Box 4)
    - Doubleday Biography of FDR, 1953 (Folder 38, Box 4)
    - Dudley, Carl, 1963 - 1966 (Folder 39, Box 4)
    - Dugmore, 1931 - 1955 (Folder 40, Box 4)
    - Dutch Treat Club, 1934 - 1981 (Folder 41, Box 4)
    - Edwards, Dan, 1929 - 1978 (Folder 42, Box 4)
    - Elkins, Frank, 1940 - 1974 (Folder 43, Box 4)
    - Gertrude Emerson, 1933 - 1981 (Folder 44, Box 4)
    - Employees, 1930 - 1980 (Folder 45, Box 4)
    - Endorsements (LT [Lowell Thomas]), 1931 - 1979 (Folder 46, Box 4)
    - Eunice's Diary, 1922 (Folder 47, Box 4)
    - European Skyways, 1926 - 1959 (Folder 48, Box 4)
    - Events, 1922 - 1923 (Folder 49, Box 4)
    - Explorers C [Club], 1928 - 1939 (Folder 50, Box 4)
    - EXC [Explorer's Clubs], 1940 - 1949 (Folder 51, Box 4)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club], 1960 - 1964 (Folder 52, Box 4)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club] (WC for E), 1965 - 1967 (Folder 53, Box 4)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club] (M3), 1968 - 1973 (Folder 54, Box 4)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club], 1950 - 1959 (Folder 1, Box 5)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club], 1974 - 1981 (Folder 2, Box 5)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club] Bust Book, 1968 - 1975 (Folder 3, Box 5)
    - EXC [Explorer's Club] MISC, undated (Folder 4, Box 5)
    - Expo, 1967 (Folder 5, Box 5)
    - Famous First Flights, 1966 - 1980 (Folder 6, Box 5)
    - Fan Mail, 1931 - 1971 (Folder 7, Box 5)
    - First World Flight, circa 1968 (Folder 8, Box 5)
    - FWF Wreckage, 1961 - 1966 (Folder 9, Box 5)
    - Fireplace, 1939 - 1981 (Folder 10, Box 5)
    - Flight Around the World, 1947 - 1964 (Folder 11, Box 5)
    - 40th Ann [Anniversary] On Air, 1970 (Folder 12, Box 5)
    - Free China Fund, 1954 - 1956 (Folder 13, Box 5)
    - FRT, 1911 - 1977 (Folder 14, Box 5)
    - Funchtman, 1961 - 1978 (Folder 15, Box 5)
    - Fur Farm, 1929 - 1946 (Folder 16, Box 5)
    - Getts, Clarck H., 1940 - 1955 (Folder 17, Box 5)
    - Gibbons, Floyed, 1930 - 1978 (Folder 18, Box 5)
    - GM, 1954 - 1975 (Folder 19, Box 5)
    - Golf - Am [American] H [Hall] of Fame, 1965 - 1978 (Folder 20, Box 5)
    - Golf - Int'l [International], 1949, 1950 (Folder 21, Box 5)
    - Golf - H [Hammersley] Hill, 1946 - 1979 (Folder 22, Box 5)
    - Grimm, Peter, 1956 - 1980 (Folder 23, Box 5)
    - Guideposts, 1945 - 1981 (Folder 24, Box 5)
    - Hall, Henry Noble, 1944 - 1948 (Folder 25, Box 5)
    - Halls of Fame, 1967 - 1981 (Folder 26, Box 5)
    - Hammersley Hill Sale, 1973 - 1981 (Folder 27, Box 5)
    - Hardy, David Keith, 1950 - 1967 (Folder 28, Box 5)
    - Hawks, Frank, 1931 - 1941 (Folder 29, Box 5)
    - Hayes, Williams P., 1953 - 1970 (Folder 30, Box 5)
    - Headless Horsemen, 1937 - 1964 (Folder 31, Box 5)
    - Herold, Don, 1936 - 1966 (Folder 32, Box 5)
    - Hicks, Ford, 1945 - 1960 (Folder 33, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure], 1957 - 1971 (Folder 34, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] 2 Scripts, undated (Folder 35, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] - Angel, 1957 - 1970 (Folder 36, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] Arctic (December 157), 1956 - 1958 (Folder 37, Box 5)
    - New G [Guinea] - High Adventure, 1957 November - 1959 (Folder 38, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] NG [New Guinea] Apprec [Appreciation], 1957 (Folder 39, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] NG [New Guinea] Comic, 1957? (Folder 40, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] NG [New Guinea], 1957 (Folder 41, Box 5)
    - High Ad [Adventure] - Tibet, 1958 February - 1964 (Folder 42, Box 5)
    - Danger I [Island] (January 1959), 1957 - 1960 (Folder 43, Box 5)
    - Morocco (May 1958) (Folder 44, Box 5)
    - Tiger - [High Adventure], 1958 April - 1959 (Folder 45, Box 5)
    - Lasseter [High Adventure], 1958 March (Folder 1, Box 6)
    - High Ad [Adventure] Timbuktu (January 1958), 1956 - 1963 (Folder 2, Box 6)
    - Holiday Hills, 1947 - 1979 (Folder 3, Box 6)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1932 - 1980 (Folder 4, Box 6)
    - Hope (Orphans), 1958 (Folder 5, Box 6)
    - How to Keep Mentally Fit, 1940 - 1941 (Folder 6, Box 6)
    - Humor, 1949 (Folder 7, Box 6)
    - Ice Men, 1952 - 1958 (Folder 8, Box 6)
    - Investments, 1934 - 1981 (Folder 9, Box 6)
    - Jay, John, 1940 - 1981 (Folder 10, Box 6)
    - Kaiser/Willys, 1953 - 1954 (Folder 11, Box 6)
    - Keddick/IPA [Intenational Platform Association]Flap, 1972 - 1973 (Folder 12, Box 6)
    - Klein, Julius, 1948 - 1975 (Folder 13, Box 6)
    - Knickerbocker Greys, 1933 - 1972 (Folder 14, Box 6)
    - Lancaster and Chester Railway, 1966 - 1975 (Folder 15, Box 6)
    - Legal and Estate Stuff, 1931 - 1983 (Folder 16, Box 6)
    - Legion of Honor, 1938 - 1952 (Folder 17, Box 6)
    - Lord Forrest (Saga and C. Chests), 1936 - 1940 (Folder 18, Box 6)
    - Lowell Thomas Remembers A. E. Smith, 1977 (Folder 19, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] on Anti - Semitism, 1941 (Folder 20, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] on Black and White, 1957 (Folder 21, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Discoverer, 1975 - 1981 (Folder 22, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Mts. [Mountains], 1948 (Folder 23, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] on News Broadcasting, 1939 - 1948 (Folder 24, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] on News Week, 1936 (Folder 25, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Obits [Obituaries], 1981 (Folder 26, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Politics, 1934 - 1981 (Folder 27, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Pub [Publication], 1925 - 1981 (Folder 28, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Rose, 1942 - 1943 (Folder 29, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] on South Seas, 1959 (Folder 30, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] on Speech (? - Aire), 1951 (Folder 31, Box 6)
    - LT[Lowell Thomas] Stationary, undated (Folder 32, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.], 1931 - 1966 (Folder 33, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.], 1956 - 1966 (Folder 34, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.], 1967 - 1981 (Folder 35, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.] Alaska Salute, 1961 (Folder 36, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.] Cin [Cinerama], 1953 - 1962 (Folder 37, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.] Management, 1935 - 1978 (Folder 38, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.] SA Pictures, 1939 - 1940 (Folder 39, Box 6)
    - LTJ [Lowell Thomas Jr.] Wedding, 1949 - 1950 (Folder 40, Box 6)
    - Mac Arthur, 1949 - 1981 (Folder 41, Box 6)
    - Maine Lumberjacks, 1937 - 1952 (Folder 42, Box 6)
    - Marco Polo Club, 1959 - 1979 (Folder 43, Box 6)
    - Marist Application, 1988 (Folder 1, Box 7)
    - Marist LT [Lowell Thomas] Awards, 1983 - 1994 (Folder 2, Box 7)
    - Marist LT [Lowell Thomas] Awards Programs, 1983 - 1991 (Folder 3, Box 7)
    - Marist LTCC [Lowell Thomas Communication Center], 1982 - 1988 (Folder 4, Box 7)
    - Matt, Toni, 1948 - 1981 (Folder 5, Box 7)
    - Matter, Fred, 1940 - 1964 (Folder 6, Box 7)
    - McDonough, Bernard, 1972 (Folder 7, Box 7)
    - McLaughlin, Bill, 1980 (Folder 8, Box 7)
    - Melton, 1948 - 1962 (Folder 9, Box 7)
    - Melzer, 1940 (Folder 10, Box 7)
    - Membership, 1933 - 1960 (Folder 11, Box 7)
    - Meta Clock, 1963 - 1977 (Folder 12, Box 7)
    - Miele flap, 1961 - 1963 (Folder 13, Box 7)
    - Miller, Malcolm, 1941 - 1979 (Folder 14, Box 7)
    - Mineral king, 1953 - 1976 (Folder 15, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1930 (Folder 16, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1931 (Folder 17, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1931 (Folder 18, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1932 (Folder 19, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1934 (Folder 20, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1935 (Folder 21, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1939 (Folder 22, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1950 (Folder 23, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1961 (Folder 24, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1962 (Folder 25, Box 7)
    - Misc, 1980 (Folder 26, Box 7)
    - Moses, Robert, 1933 - 1994 (Folder 27, Box 7)
    - Movietone, 1934 - 1976 (Folder 28, Box 7)
    - NAB/LBJ, 1946 - 1981 (Folder 29, Box 7)
    - Murray, John Creighton, 1968 - 1980 (Folder 30, Box 7)
    - NBC, 1932 - 1981 (Folder 31, Box 7)
    - Near East Foundation, 1928 - 1974 (Folder 32, Box 7)
    - Nepal, 1955 - 1973 (Folder 33, Box 7)
    - MPC [Marco Polo Club] Dinner King and Queen of Nepal, 1960 May 2 (Folder 34, Box 7)
    - Nicks, 1916 - 1982 (Folder 35, Box 7)
    - NARR (Films), 1936 - 1981 (Folder 36, Box 7)
    - Nine Old Men, 1932 - 1978 (Folder 37, Box 7)
    - Offices Rock [Rockefeller] CTR [Center], 1933 - 1964 (Folder 38, Box 7)
    - Ohio Wesleyan, 1948 - 1957 (Folder 39, Box 7)
    - Olympics, 1932 - 1980 (Folder 40, Box 7)
    - 1948 Olympics "Stranded", 1947 - 1949 (Folder 41, Box 7)
    - Overseas Press Club, 1942 - 1981 (Folder 42, Box 7)
    - Palestine, 1938 - 1957 (Folder 43, Box 7)
    - Pawling Nature Conservancy, 1958 - 1975 (Folder 44, Box 7)
    - Pawling rehab Center, 1942 - 1947 (Folder 45, Box 7)
    - Pawling, Trinity, 1934 - 1980 (Folder 46, Box 7)
    - Peale, Norman Vincent, undated (Folder 47, Box 7)
    - Perio, 1935 - 1981 (Folder 48, Box 7)
    - Pierro to George F., 1934 - 1980 (Folder 49, Box 7)
    - Pikes Peak Library, 1980 - 1981 (Folder 50, Box 7)
    - Pole to Pole Flight, 1965 (Folder 51, Box 7)
    - Post - Death, 1981 (Folder 52, Box 7)
    - Press Bulletins (Radio), 1934 (Folder 53, Box 7)
    - Press Wars, 1933 - 1944 (Folder 1, Box 8)
    - Princeton, 1914 - 1981 (Folder 2, Box 8)
    - Princeton Grad Alumni, 1944 - 1980 (Folder 3, Box 8)
    - Pryors, 1938 - 1980 (Folder 4, Box 8)
    - QH [Quaker Hill] Burial Ground Assignment, 1945 - 1981 (Folder 5, Box 8)
    - QH [Quaker Hill] - Carpenter, 1944 - 1946 (Folder 6, Box 8)
    - QHCC [Quaker Hill Country Club], 1937 - 1981 (Folder 7, Box 8)
    - QH [Quaker Hill] Reinhold, Ralph, 1938 - 1946 (Folder 8, Box 8)
    - QH [Quaker Hill] roads, 1934 - 1972 (Folder 9, Box 8)
    - Q [Quaker] Lake, 1934 - 1981 (Folder 10, Box 8)
    - Radio Pioneers, 1947 - 1955 (Folder 11, Box 8)
    - RD [Reader's Digest], 1934 - 1981 (Folder 12, Box 8)
    - RD [Reader's Digest] Foundation, 1948 - 1975 (Folder 13, Box 8)
    - Redwoods (QH), 1950 - 1962 (Folder 14, Box 8)
    - Remote, 1930 - 1966 (Folder 15, Box 8)
    - Requests, 1940s (Folder 16, Box 8)
    - Req 1960s Sawyer, Johnny, 1958 - 1968 (Folder 17, Box 8)
    - Requests - Endorse, 1935 - 1981 (Folder 18, Box 8)
    - Requests - Money, 1933 - 1981 (Folder 19, Box 8)
    - Richardson, Hugh, 1953 - 1980 (Folder 20, Box 8)
    - Roberts, John, 1942 - 1975 (Folder 21, Box 8)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1932 - 1982 (Folder 22, Box 8)
    - FDR Banquet, 1939 (Folder 23, Box 8)
    - St. Peter, Ann, 1940 - 1975 (Folder 24, Box 8)
    - Sawyer, John P., 1943 - 1978 (Folder 25, Box 8)
    - Schoonmaker, Frank, 1930 - 1943 (Folder 26, Box 8)
    - Scott, Henry L., 1950 (Folder 27, Box 8)
    - Scripts (Misc.), 1932 - 1950 (Folder 28, Box 8)
    - Sepalla, 1961 - 1968 (Folder 29, Box 8)
    - Seraphics, 1946 - 1975 (Folder 30, Box 8)
    - Shane, Ted, 1938 - 1967 (Folder 31, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1968 (Folder 32, Box 8)
    - June 1970 Siberia, 1970 - 1974 (Folder 33, Box 8)
    - Simpson, Anita, 1939 - 1957 (Folder 34, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1933 - 1952 (Folder 35, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1953 - 1957 (Folder 36, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1960 - 1964 (Folder 37, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1965 - 1967 (Folder 38, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1969 - 1972 (Folder 39, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1973 - 1976 (Folder 40, Box 8)
    - Ski, 1977 - 1994 (Folder 41, Box 8)
    - Ski - Allais, 1948 - 1949 (Folder 42, Box 8)
    - Ski - Law, 1941 - 1948 (Folder 43, Box 8)
    - Ski - Mont Tremblant, 1938 - 1974 (Folder 44, Box 8)
    - Ski (Mt Mansfield, Rusch, Chimo, Stowe), 1942 - 1975 (Folder 45, Box 8)
    - National Ski Patrol, 1939 - 1976 (Folder 46, Box 8)
    - Ski - Sahuaro Ski Club, 1944 - 1958 (Folder 47, Box 8)
    - Ski - Ski Bob, 1968 - 1970 (Folder 48, Box 8)
    - Smith, Frank, 1945 - 1966 (Folder 49, Box 8)
    - Smith, Ross, 1921 (Folder 50, Box 8)
    - Smith - Johannsen, 1968 - 1978 (Folder 51, Box 8)
    - Softball, So What?, 1938 (Folder 52, Box 8)
    - South Am, 1943 (Folder 53, Box 8)
    - South America Broadcast, 1957? (Folder 54, Box 8)
    - Speak, 1932 - 1978 (Folder 55, Box 8)
    - Speech Notes (MIsc, undated), 1930 - 1980 (Folder 56, Box 8)
    - Storrs, 1939 (Folder 57, Box 8)
    - Strange (Bowen) (See Doubleday), 1967 - 1979 (Folder 58, Box 8)
    - Stranger Letters, 1967 - 1972 (Folder 59, Box 8)
    - Strom, 1937 - 1970 (Folder 60, Box 8)
    - Sun 1 of [?], 1934 (Folder 61, Box 8)
    - Sun, 1942 - 1944 (Folder 62, Box 8)
    - Sun Dealer's Meetings and Film, 1934 (Folder 63, Box 8)
    - Syracuse Debacle, 1947 (Folder 64, Box 8)
    - Tagore, 1970 (Folder 65, Box 8)